A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, United States International Affairs Program (USIAP), Education and Culture, Office Files of Barbara Hatton FA602
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, United States International Affairs Program (USIAP), Education and Culture, Office Files of Barbara Hatton
1988-1993
Rockefeller Archive Center
Hatton, Barbara
Ford Foundation
FA602
3.8 Cubic Feet 10 letter document containers
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary. In 2019, more of Barbara Hatton's files were transferred to RAC by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2019:094 and 2019:095.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series, Correspondence, which is further divided into two subseries: 1) Alpha Chrons and 2) Monthly Chron Files
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of correspondence created by Barbara Hatton during the course of her work as K-12 program officer and Deputy Director of the Education and Culture program at the Ford Foundation between 1988 and 1993. The majority of the correspondence is between Dr. Hatton and grant applicants. When Dr. Hatton left the Foundation in 1993, Alison Bernstein, Director of the Education and Culture program, took responsibility for her correspondence.
Biographical / Historical
Barbara Hatton worked as a Deputy Director of the Education and Culture Program and a K-12 Program Officer at the Ford Foundation from 1988-1993. She was primarily focused on two programs 1.) a program to correct the shortage of minority teachers in schools throughout the country and 2.) a program focused on improving education in rural areas. Dr. Hatton left the Foundation in 1993 to serve as the president of South Carolina State University.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Access to education; Education -- Minorities; Education, Rural; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation -- Education grantmaking; School improvement programs
- Correspondence, 1; 3.8 Cubic Feet 10 letter document boxes
  - Alpha Chron, 1
    - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
    - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
    - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 9-13)
    - 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14-17, Box 4, Folder 18)
    - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19-22, Box 5, Folder 23-25)
    - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 26-27, Box 6, Folder 28)
      Scope and Contents
      Alison Bernstein took over Barbara Hatton's correspondence when she left to become president of South Carolina State University in February 1993.
  - Monthly Chron Files, 2
    - 1988 November-December (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
    - Internal Correspondence, 1989 January-February (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - 1989 January-September (Box 6, Folder 32-39)
    - 1990 January-December (Box 6, Folder 40-43, Box 7, Folder 44-51)
    - 1991 January-December (Box 7, Folder 52, Box 8, Folder 53-63)
    - 1992 January-December (Box 9, Folder 64-71, Box 10, Folder 72-75)
    - 1993 January-December (Box 10, Folder 76-87)